# **Jacob Liberman**

jacobliberman@gmail.com

Austin, TX

## **Summary**

Prouct manager with a professional background in open source software development, data analysis, and high performance computing (HPC). Extensive experience working with the US Federal Government and in LATAM. Multiple industry and academic publications. Frequent presenter at technology conferences. Ability to context switch between C-level strategic planning and engineering-level technical discussions.

## **Experience**

## Principal Product Manager, OpenStack

Red Hat, November 2016 - Present

• Red Hat is an enterprise software company with an open source development model. I work with Red Hat's strategic customers on feature development, bug fix, executive strategy, and private cloud implementation and design.

## **Principal Software Engineer, Cloud Computing**

Red Hat, January 2012 - November 2016

• Developed, tested, and published cloud computing reference architectures based on Red Hat OpenStack Platform, Enterprise Linux, and Hadoop.

## **Rugby 7s Head Coach**

University of Texas at Austin, August 2010 – July 2015

• Founder and coach of University of Texas Rugby 7s team. Ranked #20 2011, #13 2012, #12 2013 out of more than 500 college rugby programs.

## Performance analyst

Philippine Rugby Football Union, June 2013 – August 2013

• National team performance analyst during the 2013 Rugby 7s World Cup in Moscow, Russia. Video capture, coding, statistical analysis, and scouting.

## Performance Engineer, Scientific and Cloud Computing

Advanced Micro Devices, November 2009 – January 2012

• Designed and conducted server performance studies for competitive analysis. Helped customers improve the performance of their codes on our systems. Managed lab clusters for remote customer evaluation. Traveled to customer sites to conduct benchmarks for acceptance testing.

## **Development Engineer, High Performance Computing**

Dell, August 2006 - November 2009

• Lead performance engineer. Conducted server performance studies using standard benchmarks and applications. Shared results via publications and presentations. Evaluated storage, networking, and software technologies for inclusion in our product.

## **Curriculum Designer/Subject Matter Expert**

Dell, February 2005 - August 2006

• Developed classroom and online technical curriculum for the field consulting team. High Performance Computing (HPC) subject matter expert.

## **Services Consulting Engineer**

Dell, April 1999 - February 2005

• Remote field services and support engineer. I helped customers deploy EMC storage arrays and attach UNIX and Linux servers to them.

## **Education**

#### **Texas State University**

Master's Program, Computer Science

->30 hours of upper division (grad and undergrad) CS course work 3.8 GPA

## The University of Texas at Austin

Master's Degree, Technology in Education

- 4.0 GPA with course work in learning theory, statistics, and scientific computing.

#### **University of Wisconsin-Madison**

Bachelor's Degree, English Literature

- Creative writing emphasis

#### **Volunteer Service**

#### **Board** member

Trojans Pop Warner, *August 2015 – 2017* 

Web services board member and volunteer American football coach. We promote safe and effective tackling by teaching rugby tackle techniques to all age groups. (5-12)

## Treasurer — Texas Rugby Alumni Network

Texas Exes, May 2015 - Present

Board member of the Texas Rugby Alumni Association, an official chapter of the Texas Exes. We organize alumni events and manage an endowed scholarship fund.

# **Selected Publications, Example Code**

https://github.com/jliberma